melbournewater.com.au 2019-04-08

# Privacy website statement | Melbourne Water

​We respect the privacy of your personal information and are committed to collecting and handling it responsibly and in accordance with Victoria's Privacy and Data Protection Act 2014.

The following privacy statement applies to the entire Melbourne Water website, what personal information is collected and how it is handled. The statement does not extend beyond this website. If you visit other sites from this website you should familiarise yourself with their privacy statements.

For general information about how we seek to protect your personal information, please visit [our privacy policy page](https://www.melbournewater.com.au/about-us/publications-and-policies/legislation-and-policies/policies-and-procedures/privacy-policy). You can also download the full policy here.

Privacy policy64.14 KB (PDF)   

## ​What information do we collect?

We only collect personal information online when you choose to provide it, for example if you are paying a bill.

You can visit our website anonymously. Statistical information is collected each time you visit the website so we can calculate such things as:

  * the number of site visitors

  * the time and duration of site visits

  * page impressions

  * site traffic

We collect this information to evaluate the performance of our online services and product offerings – no individual website user is identified.

## Cookies

Cookies are used throughout Melbourne Water's website. Cookies are pieces of information that a website transfers to your computer's hard disk for record-keeping purposes.

We use cookies:

  * to determine if you have previously visited our site

  * to identify the pages and third party websites you have accessed

If you do not wish to accept cookies you can set your browser to refuse them. However, cookies allow you to fully utilise all our website services and we encourage you to accept them.

## Google reCAPTCHA

We use a Google-provided tool called "reCAPTCHA" which, on some form submissions, is intended to tell humans from robots to prevent abuse of those forms by spam bots. The reCAPTCHA tool may, in its algorithm, make use of cookies as well as other information like IP address, date, time, language, screen size and resolution, and mouse movements while on the page. The reCAPTCHA tool is subject to Google’s [terms of use](https://policies.google.com/terms?hl=en) and[ privacy policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en).

## Use and disclosure of information

We will only use or disclose information about you for the purpose for which you provided it – for example, to respond to a request for information. We will only use or disclose your personal information for a secondary purpose with your consent, or where the Privacy and Data Protection Act 2014 otherwise authorises the use or disclosure.

## Access to your personal information

To seek access to your personal information held by Melbourne Water, or to correct or update your personal information, contact us on 131 722 or contact us online.

## Security

Melbourne Water is committed to holding your personal information securely. All stored information is protected from unauthorised access through the use of secure passwords and user log on or other security procedures.

This website also contains a business-trading sub-site that is operated by Melbourne Water and the Westpac Banking group. This sub-site enables Melbourne Water to accept online payments from you, using your credit card.

When Westpac captures data for online payments it is passed through a secure server using encryption technology to ensure that your information is protected when being sent over the Internet. This process does not involve Melbourne Water having access to, or collecting or recording, your credit card information.

## Email addresses

Email addresses will only be used or stored to respond to specific user queries. They will not be used or stored for any unrelated purposes or disclosed to third parties.

If you are a registered user with Melbourne Water’s business sub-site we may, if you agree, use your email address to notify you of changes in services. Melbourne Water will only email registered users who have asked to receive email updates or bulletins. Registered users can cancel this email service offer at any time.

## Want to know more?

If you require further information regarding this privacy statement, please contact us on 131 722 or contact us online.
